# **Amita Yadav**

Sector 70, Noida, Uttar Pradesh9625682697, 8285318724

# Software Engineer

# Summary

**Focused and quick-learning Software Engineer** with 1+ years of experience in the development of Web & Enterprise applications using JAVA and Scala. Updates functionality based on customer requirements to ensure an excellent user experience.

Hands-on experience in Core Java, Scala, Rust, JDBC, Wicket, Actix, Play.

Hands-on experience in Agile Methodologies for the development of the projects.

Cohesive team worker, having strong analytical, problem-solving and interpersonal skills.

I have been a mentor, code reviewer, pair programmer for the interns.

I also write blogs and give Meetups.

# Work experience

### **Software Engineer**

July 2019 - Present

VIRTUAL EMPLOYEE PVT LTD

Being a Scala Developer, I am working on EA (Enterprise Architecture) based API in functional programming language i.e Scala and Java.

- Working on a particular module named Visualizations, of the project that is related to the UI part of the application.
- Direct interaction with the Client
- Enhancing the features of the application as per user satisfaction

### **Software Consultant**

July 2018 - April 2019

**KNOLDUS INC** 

As a Software Consultant, I worked on micro-service architecture based web API in emerging technology Rust inspired by Lagom application "Online Auction". I had been the only programmer responsible for development and deployment.

- Analyzing the Lagom application and creating the stories.
- I do sprint planning, sprint grooming, estimating story points and stand-up.
- Documenting the architectural details, API handshake documents, and outcomes of the POCs.
- Coding, Unit testing, Code Coverage, Code Reviewing and Customizing.
- Giving a demo to the client and do Retrospectives.

Held additional roles as Mentor, Code Reviewer and Pair Programmer for the interns.

# **Projects**

### 1. Smart360

It is an Enterprise Architecture Management based application that handles the data of any entity and manages it.

**Tech Stacks:** Scala, Java, Apache Wicket, Orientdb, D3, Javascript, HTML5

Role: Scala Developer + Java Developer

### 2. Rustify

It is a web application for an online auction portal based on microservice architecture inspired by Lagom Online Auction.

Tech Stacks: Rust, Git, Actix, Tarpaulin, Cargo, Futures, Kafka, REST

Role: Software Consultant

### 3. **HAWK**

It is an IOT application for two-way authentication of personnel entering the gate, by his/her punch card as well as an image of the personnel.

Tech Stacks: Rust, Java, Raspberry Pi, AWS S3, AWS Lambda, AWS gateway, Kafka, Terraform, Docker

Role: Mentor, Code Reviewer, and Pair Programmer

# Internship/Training

### **Software Consultant Trainee**

July 2018 - December 2018

Knoldus Inc

As an Intern, I went through many technology stacks:

• Java 8, TDD, Git, Maven, Scala, Akka, Kafka, DevOps, Jenkins, Aws ec2, docker, Spark, QA, Html5, CSS, Bootstrap, Javascript, Ajax, Angular

Trainee June 2017 - Aug 2017

Ducat

Technology: Core Java

# **Skills**

Languages	Java JDK series 5, 6, 7, 8, Rust, Scala, C++, C
Tools	JUnit, Visual VM, Postman, Jira, Github, Bitbucket, Apache POI
Frameworks	Play, Lagom, Actix, Wicket
Databases	Scylladb, Casssandra, MySQL , SQL
Others	OOPS, Scrum, Git, TDD, REST, JSON, Unit testing, Logger, IntelliJ, Webstorm, Eclipse
Build tools	Maven, Sbt, Cargo

# **Education**

# Bachelors of Technology Raj Kumar Goel Institute of Technology Computer Science & Engineering with 78.4% Intermediate Vishnu Bhagwan Public School & College, Allahabad PCM with 74.8% High School Vishnu Bhagwan Public School & College, Allahabad Scored 9.6 CGPA

### Certifications

- Reactive Architecture Series by Cognitive Class:
  - -> CQRS & Event Sourcing
  - -> Distributed Messaging Patterns
  - -> Building Scalable Sysyems
  - -> Reactive Micro-services
  - -> Introduction to Reactive Systems
  - -> Domain Driven Design
- "Rust for Undergrads" by Udemy.

# **Achievements**

- Blogs published on Knoldus Site: https://blog.knoldus.com/author/amitayadav27/
- Blog published on Signify Technology: https://www.signifytechnology.com/blog/2019/02/structure-your-data-in-rust-by-amita-yadav
- Meetup on you-tube: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=dl5jYsSgVpM
- Won the first prize in **DEBUGGING** at TechSparks#17, inter-college competition in 2017.
- Won the first prize in **BACKTRACKING** at TechSparks#17, inter-college competition in 2017.